《星际之门亚特兰蒂斯》  前情回顾
Previously on Stargate Atlantis...
我确定昨晚我看到了一个梦境
I believe I had a vision last night.
我见到了我儿子的父亲  迦楠
I saw Kanaan, the father of my son.
-救救我们  -你在哪里
- Save us. - Where are you?
幽灵战斗机!
Dart!
正如你所请求  我为你而来
I came for you, just like you asked.
是我要求的
Like I asked.
-迈克尔  -在你梦境中的人是我
- Michael. - I was the one in your visions.
我被及时地送回来了?
I was sent back in time?
不  事实上你被提早送回来了
No, in fact, you were sent forward.
你失踪后
I've loaded all the intel
有关迈克尔的情报已经被全部载入了
we got on Michael after your disappearance,
包括我们找到泰勒的地方
including the address where we found Teyla.
快
Quickly.
-你必须放了我  -泰勒
- You must release me. - Teyla.
-约翰  -我知道泰勒的下落了
- John. - I know where Teyla is.
我的孩子不关你的事
My child is of no concern to you.
我为他计划好了未来
I have great plans for him.
我想我们来得太早了
I think we're too early,
但他会把她带到这里分娩
but he'll bring her here to have the baby.
这是个陷阱  我们必须马上离开这里!
Colonel, it's a boobytrap. We must get outta here, now!
太完美了
This is perfect.
正是我所要的
Just what I needed.
为刚忙完的几个星期干杯
To the has been hectic several weeks.
怎么不说是四年
Try four years.
说的没错
Very true.
你看  它使这平凡的一刻更加与众不同
You know what, it makes these common moments even more special.
我很珍惜我们两人在一起的时光
I cherish these times, when it's just you and me.
我也是
Me too.
你明天还要早起
You... you've got an early morning.
我从来没好好的谢过你
I never got to properly thank you.
为什么
For what?
什么为什么
为你救了我
For rescuing me.
从迈克尔手里
From Michael.
我从没放弃希望  因为我知道
I never gave up hope because I knew...
我知道约翰你会回来救我的
I knew that you would come for me, John.
这听起来很荒唐  但...
I know this sounds crazy, but...
我不记得
I don't remember...
曾救过你
rescuing you.
你不记得是因为你确实没有救过她
You don't remember rescuing her because you didn't.
就像你从来没救过我
Just like you never rescued me.
谢帕德
Sheppard!
老兄
Hey, buddy.
-发生什么了  -迈克尔的场子塌了
- What happened? - Michael's compound collapsed on us.
我想我...
I think I... I...
坚持住  让我来瞧瞧
Yeah, hold on. Let me take a look.
那是什么鬼东西
What the hell was that?
一个旧碎片  没什么大不了的
Just old scrap, no big deal.
其他人怎么样了
What about the others?
我不清楚  我们被分开了
I don't know. We got separated.
试试用无线电联系他们
Try them on the radio.
没信号  这儿干扰太多
Still no signal. There's too much interference.
我的腿一定是断了
Pretty sure my leg is broken.
我想我的情况倒还不错
I think I'm remarkably fine.
那不是很好吗
Isn't that wonderful?
让我舒了一口气  谢谢
That brings me great comfort, thank you.
我想我们埋得不是很深  能看见阳光
I don't think we're that deep. I can see daylight.
如果我能...
If I can just...
-道歉  - 我让埃迪生守在入口处了
- Sorry. - I posted Edison at the entrance.
他会去找支援的
He'll get help.
如果他没被碎片砸到的话
That is assuming he wasn't hit by falling debris.
博士
Doc,
代达罗斯号离开亚特兰蒂斯时
The Dedalus left Atlantis
我们是在确认谢帕德所讲的故事
when we were still confirming Sheppard's story.
那样算起来
With that kind of a headstart,
他们应该会在三小时内到达这里
they should be here in less than three hours.
所以不管怎么说  救援队一定在路上了
So one way or the other, help is on the way.
抱歉  只是空间狭小使我不舒服
I'm sorry. It's just I'm not good in tight spaces.
这里没有敌人  好不?
Look, there's no bad guys around, okay?
没坏人  只有一大片的废墟  所以...
No bad guys, just a lot of debris. So...
如果你给我坐好了别乱动
if you could please just sit tight
不要让上面的废墟掉下来  就万幸了
and try not to make the ceiling collapse, that would be great.
好的  没坏人
Okay. No bad guys.
坐着不动
Just... just sit tight.
-你什么时候得到这个的  -几个月前
- When did you get this? - Moments ago.
计划有变
Change of plans.
设定新航线
We're setting a new course.
我们的场子已经失守了
Our compound has been compromised.
外来临时激活
Unscheduled off-world activation.
是中尉埃迪生的虹膜解除码
It's lieutenant Edison's IDC.
发生了什么  你的同伴呢
What happened? Where's your team?
发生了一个大爆炸
There was a massive explosion.
所有人都在那个主场里时
Everyone was in the main compound,
整个场子就突然崩塌了
the whole building imploded on itself.
-有生还者吗  -无线电通讯设备失效了
- Were there any survivors? - Radios are down.
不知道  我只想要先回来报告
I don't know. I just thought I should get back here.
不  你做得很好  把他带去医务室
No, you did the right thing. Get him to the infirmary.
-代达罗斯号还有多远  -还有两小时
- How far away is the Daedalus? - Still two hours out.
我们不能再等了
We can't wait that long.
让工程兵集合起来
Have the combat engineers gear up
让凯勒医生准备出发
and Doctor Keller ready her away team.
是的  长官
Yes, ma'am.
-你在干什么  -我有幽闭恐惧症
- What are you doing? - I'm claustrophobic.
我正忙着集中注意力  这很不容易
I'm trying to keep my mind busy, which is hard,
因为你知道这...
because you know, it's...
是我的注意力
my mind.
大爆炸后不可能留下什么有用的东西
Well, there's no way anything useful survived that implosion.
说你自己吧
Speak for yourself.
博士  你知道我是什么意思
You know what I mean, Doc.
我找到了一堆电脑部件
I found a bunch of computer parts.
主板不是烧焦就是绷断
The mother boards are all fried or snapped.
而这些硬件可能完好无损
But these hard drives might still be intact.
如果我能接通电源...
If I can just get the power to...
怎么了  有什么好消息
What is it? Something good?
不知道  一下子出来很多信息
I don't know, a lot of information.
等等
Hold on.
我想我中六合彩了
I think I just hit the jackpot.
有办法发出信号了?
Some way to broadcast a signal?
让他们知道我们的位置
Let people know our location,
好快点来救我  还是什么
speed up the rescue? What?
不  虽是事后诸葛亮  不过你是对的
No, although in hindsight, you're right,
那真等于中头奖了
that should be considered the jackpot.
这只是个硬件  只能读取它上面的信息
But, no, this is a hardrive, I can only access what's on it.
什么信息
Which is?
是爆炸中保存下来的迈克尔的日志
It's Michael's wiki. It survived the explosion.
-那是什么  -迈克尔的数据库
- The what? - Michael's database.
里面有大量甚至所有的资料
A large chunk, maybe the whole thing.
我是说我们得到了基本简图
I mean we've got base schematics,
医疗研究资料  行星列表...
medical research information, list of planets...
-你知道这意味着什么吗  -是啊
- I mean, you know what this means? - Yeah.
意味着我们仍困在这里  外加断条腿
It means we're still stuck here and I still have a broken leg.
那只是暂时的  但如果我们能离开这
In the short term. But if we get out of here...
如果?
If?
他还在外面  会找人来的  如果迈克尔...
We'd have him on the run, he'd be finished. Look, if Michael...
不好
Oh no.
什么
What?
鉴于你现在伤势
I don't want to concern you any more
我不想雪上加霜
than you actually already are,
如果我没看错的话  那么迈克尔他...
but if I'm reading this correctly, then Michael is...
-闭嘴  -你闭嘴  这很重要
- Shut up. - You shut up. This is important.
-如果迈克尔是...  -别出声
- If Michael is... - Quit making noise.
有脚步声
It's footsteps.
好吧  改变计划  快大声叫啊
Okay, revise that. Start making noise.
在下面!
Down here!
-我们在下面  -快来救救我们!
- We're down here! - Help!
检测到四个生命迹象  分别在两个地方
All right, we've got four life signs in two different locations.
有两个人就在我们正下方
First two should be right beneath us.
-听  -我们在下面
- Listen! - We're down here!
麦凯  是你吗
McKay, is that you?
谢天谢地  是的
Oh, thank God. Yes!
-我和罗恩被困在底下了  -你们还好吧
- I'm trapped down here with Lorne. - Are you okay?
-我们很好  -博士  你在说什么!
- Were fine! - Hey Doc!
对了  罗恩的腿断了
Right, right, right. Okay, Lorne's got a broken leg.
呆着别动  我们有工程兵在这
Stay put. We've got combat engineers here.
我们会把你们救出来的
We're going to dig you out.
快点
Hurry up!
罗德尼  安全的前提下我们会尽量快的
We work as fast as is safe, Rodney.
不  你们不明白
No, you don't understand.
我发现自毁程序一旦启动
I found out that when the selfdestruct is initiated,
就会自动引爆亚空间
it's automatically programmed to send a subspace burst.
迈克尔很可能已经在路上了
Michael's probably already on his way.
看起来他们并不是陷得太深
It doesn't look like they're too far down.
一个小时内应该可以把他们救出来
We should be able to get them out inside of an hour.
但其他两个人怎么办
But what about the other two?
他们埋得深多了
They're a lot deeper.
代达罗斯号很快就会到了
Well, the Daedalus will be here soon,
到时就可以把他们传送出来  对吗
so we can just beam them out, right?
只是要赶在迈克尔前头
As long as Michael doesn't get here first.
好吧  我们开工了
All right, let's get started.
里维斯  开艘小飞船进入太空轨道
Rivers, take a Jumper into orbit
密切注意迈克尔的飞船
and keep a look out for Michael's ship.
一看见他马上报告
Let me know the second he gets here.
一
One,
二
two,
三
three.
这东西完全不动
This thing ain't moving.
其他人怎么样了
What happened to the others?
我不晓得
I don't know.
崩塌发生地太快  没多少人能逃出来
It happened pretty quickly, not that many people made it out.
我太傻了
I'm so stupid.
这建筑明显是个陷阱
Of course the building was booby trapped.
-我应该早看出来的  -我们没人看出来
- I should have seen that coming. - Yeah, well none of us did.
-是的  但...  -什么
- Yeah, but... - What?
我是个男人  你知道...
I'm the guy, you know...
是"男人"的男人
like "the guy".
每个人都知道我们面对的是什么
Everyone knew what we were getting into.
我们都知道这有多危险
We all knew how dangerous it was
所以不要一棍子把自己打死
so don't beat yourself up about it.
你应该好好想想
You need to start thinking about
怎么把自己从这里弄出来
how to crawl your way outta here.
没有办法
No way.
说真的  你只要一直往上爬  推开残骸
Serious, you just keep moving up, keep moving the debris.
一步一步来
Work your way up.
谢帕德  我是不会丢下你不管的
I'm not leaving you behind, Sheppard.
我可不是逞英雄
I'm not trying to be a hero here.
只是为自己着想
It's a selfish thing.
你得挖个洞
I need you to dig a hole
这样救援队才能下来救我们
so that the rescuers can come down and get me.
老大  你搞错了
It's the wrong way, chief.
把这个梁挪开  你就能出来了
If we get this beam out of you, we get you free.
然后我们一起挖  好不
We'll dig ourselves out together. Deal?
无论如何你都不会听我的  是吧
You're not gonna listen to me one way or the other, are you?
说的没错
Great deal.
太好了
Excellent.
真是太好了
This is all very good.
你的儿子很快就要出生了
Your son should be making an appearance any day now.
我想听到这消息你该开心才是
I thought that would make you happy.
怀着孩子对你来说
I can't imagine carrying a child inside of you
肯定很不舒服
is very comfortable.
我不会伤害他的
I will not harm him.
-为什么你不接受呢  -因为我了解你
- Why can't you just accept that? - Because I know you.
大千世界
All these worlds filled with people
可怜的人类一生忙碌而终
busying themselves with their pathetic lives.
他们来了又走  生了又死
They come and they go, they live and they die,
银河系对他们已足够  而你的儿子...
and the galaxy is no better for it, but your son...
你的儿子是变革之子
your son will be an instrument of change.
他会被这些时代所铭记
He will be remembered for the ages.
那他的母亲呢
And what of his mother?
你总说他的未来  从未谈及我  为什么
You speak often of his future, but never of mine, why is that?
我希望你可以...
I'd hoped that you would...
-我希望你可以理解  -到时间了
- I had hoped that you would understand. - It's time.
很好
Very well.
解除手铐  安排守卫在门口把守
Remove the restraints and post a guard outside this door.
我必须在孩子出生前逃离这里
I must escape before our child is born.
一旦我没有利用价值  他就会杀了我
He will kill me once I'm of no use to him.
-我不能  -迦楠  为什么
- I can't. - Kanaan, why?
-这太危险了  -对谁来说
- It is too dangerous. - For who?
他会杀了我们
He will kill us.
杀了全部人
Kill us all.
是的  他会动手的
Yes, he will.
不管你是否帮我都一样
Whether you help me or not,
他一利用完就会丢弃你  你还不明白么
you are disposable to him, can you not see that?
听我说
Listen to me.
迦楠
Kanaan.
拜托你
Please.
求求你了!
Please!
来这边
Come over here.
我很好  只是些擦伤
I'm fine, it's just a couple scratches.
罗德尼·麦凯拒绝接受治疗
Rodney McKay refusing medical help,
一定有什么事不对劲
now I really know there's something wrong.
说正经的  我还好  你好好照顾罗恩
Seriously, I'm okay, just you should look after Lorne.
还有其他生还者吗
Any survivors?
我们还发现还有两个活着
We found two other life signs
但他们被埋地更深一些
but they're burried under a lot more debris.
所以要多花点时间
So it's going to take a little longer.
但我们正在努力施救
I've got people working on it.
知道是谁吗
We know who it is?
还无法确认
Not yet.
-找到泰勒了吗  -还没
-Did you find Teyla?  -No.
但谢帕德是对的
But I think Sheppard was right.
他要带她来这里了  我们来早了
He was gonna bring her here.We just came to soon.
-卡特上校  -请讲
-Colonel Carter.  -Go ahead.
在外太空发现幽灵巡洋舰
Ma'am, a Wraith cruiser just came out of hyperspace.
迈克尔要来了
Michael's here.
出现大量生命迹象
Multiple life signs.
一定是亚特兰蒂斯的人
It must be the Atlantians.
他们在搜索废墟
They're combing the debris.
但他们肯定知道留在那太危险了
But they must know it's too dangerous to stay here.
他们在寻找幸存者
They're searching for survivors.
这次不会再失败了
This might not be a total loss,after all.
所有人回到飞船
Everyone, fall back to your Jumpers!
敌人来了
We got incoming!
好枪法
Good shot!
大家退回飞船
Let's fall back to our Jumpers.
我们还有人被困在底下
We still got men trapped down here.
他们得等等了  现在也不能把他们挖出来
They'll have to wait.We're no good to them out.
快点  退回去
Let's go! Fall back!
-把飞船隐形  -是
- Cloak the ship.  - Got it!
我们得到信号  星门要被激活了
We're getting a reading.The Gate's been activated.
这是幽灵族的作战方式
Wraith battle technique:
拨号  锁住一切  困住所有人
dial the Gate, lock everyone out,make sure they can't escape.
-好方法  -但他们可不是笨蛋
- Well it's a good one.- Well, they're not idiots.
越来越多幽灵战斗机靠近废墟了
We got more darts on the way and they got troups on the debris field.
他们肯定是知道我们还有人在下面
Must know we got people there.
-我们有多少飞船  -加上这艘有三架
- How many Jumpers do we have?  - Three including this one.
对方有超过20架
I'm reading over twenty darts!
但他们应该看不到我们吧
But they can't see us though, right?
我们隐形时是无法开火的
We can't fire while we're cloaked.
他们同样要花点时间才能把人挖出来
Look, it's gonna take them time to dig them out. The same as us.
我们在这等代达罗斯号
We wait for the Daedalus.
罗德尼  进入轨道吧
Rodney, take us into orbit.
幽灵战斗机进入最小阻力
Darts reporting minimal resistance.
他们已经开始搜索废墟了
They've started searching the debris.
我们要快点  必须要活口
We must work fast.I need them alive.
就是这个
Here it is.
-那就是迈克尔的巡洋舰  -好像是
- Is that Michael's cruiser?  - Well, it looks like it.
这意味着泰勒在那船上吗
Does that mean that Teyla's on that ship?
有可能
It's possible.
太好了  不是吗
Well, that's great, though, right?
代达罗斯号来时  就能将她传输过来
When the Daedalus shows up we can just beam her up too, no?
没那么简单
It's not as easy as that.
可能迈克尔已经把她转移了
Chances are Michael has already removed her transmitter.
就算没有
And even if he hasn't,
环绕在幽灵巡洋舰周围的电磁波
Wraith cruisers surround themselves with
也会干扰我们的射线
an electromagnetic jamming field.
光束无法进去  也无法出来
No beaming in, no beaming out.
我们是近在咫尺啊
We're so close.
再试试吧
How about one more try?
我没力了  老兄
I feel pretty weak, buddy.
你不会对我没信心吧
You're not quiting on me yet, are you?
不会
No.
我刚刚还在考虑这个问题
I was thinking about it.
你要知道这不是你要考虑的
You know this is part of our deal?
你对这个决定还有意见啊
You keep adding things to this deal of ours.
准备
Ready?
一
One,
二
two,
三
three.
你自己走吧
I need you to get outta here.
如果我被困住了你会抛弃我吗
Would you leave me if I was stuck under there?
会
Yes.
你听到没
You hear that?
什么
What?
挖掘的声音
It sounds like digging.
是的
Yeah.
他们来了
They're here.
我们在下面
We're down here!
我们来救你们了  挺住啊
We're coming for you, just stay calm!
还打算放弃吗
And you were gonna quit.
发现另一艘飞船行踪
Reading another ship in orbit.
是幽灵巡洋舰
It's a Wraith cruiser.
展开防护盾  准备光波武器
Shields up.Ready forward beam weapons.
长官  卡特上校发来密报
Sir, I'm receiving a coded transmission from Colonel Carter.
-萨曼  怎么回事  -长话短说
-Sam, what's going on?  -Long story for short
那是迈克尔的巡洋舰
that's Michael's cruiser and
泰勒好像就在那里
he likely has Teyla onboard.
这样的话  我们就不能炸毁它了
So I can't blow him out of the sky.
恐怕不能
No, I'm afraid not.
舰队遭受攻击  防护盾已打开
We're taken fire, sir.Shields are holding.
我们攻击前他们已经展开防御了
They managed to get the shields up before we hit them.
这太不幸了
That's unfortunate.
增强能量超光速推进
Transfer power to the hyperdrive.
那些战斗机怎么办
What about the Darts?
必要的损失
Acceptable losses.
他准备撤离了
He's running.
可以的话全力攻击它的超光速推进器
Not if I can help it.Target his hyperdrive.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
我们失去超光速系统了
We've lost hyperdrive!
我知道正面对抗在所难免了
I guess we're fighting, after all.
防护盾下降了百分之八十
Shields are down to 80%.
代达罗斯号  我们还有2人被困在星球
Daedalus, we still have two people on the planet.
超光速系统要赶到那里只是时间问题
And it's just a matter of time before the hybrids reach them.
你能扫描一下传输信号吗
Can you scan for transmitter signals?
镇定点  马上就到了
Stay calm. We're almost there.
以后我再也不拿工程兵开玩笑了
I'm gonna stop making fun of combat engineers.
从今天开始  我发誓
As of today, I promise.
赫利什也跟你们在一起吗
Is Herrish up there with you?
是的  他在这呢  别着急
Yeah, he's here! Don't worry,
很快就可以把你们弄出去了
we'll have you out soon.
唐·赫利什至少下个月才能回来
Don Herrish is on leave until next month.
等会我们出去后
If we get outta here,
兄弟们  我请喝酒
beer is on me, boys.
你想喝点什么
What do you like?
达夫啤酒?
Duff beer?
还是欧普拉麦酒
Or Oprah Ale?
达夫吧
Duff
看来他们没看过"辛普森一家"
Well, they don't watch The Simpsons,
也从不喝酒
or drink beer.
是迈克尔的超光速系统
Michael's hybrids.
可能他是倒塌时被困住了
Maybe he was tipped off when the builing blew up.
我都说刚刚应该离开这里的
You totally should have gotten out of here.
不管了
Yeah, whatever.
我拿不到枪
I can't reach my gun.
给
Here.
好的
All right.
你想怎么玩
How do you wanna play this?
战斗到最后一刻
Shoot until we can't shoot anymore.
好吧  就这样
All right.
荣幸之至
Been a pleasure.
同感
Same.
找到他们了  是谢帕德上校和若楠
We got 'em.It's Colonel Sheppard and Ronon.
可以把他们光波传送上来吗
Can you beam them up?
这样的话要撤掉防护盾
We'd have to drop our shields,
这可不是好主意
I kind of think that'd be a bad idea right now.
如果迈克尔先得手  会杀了他们的
If Michael gets his hands on them,he'll kill them.
我们别无选择
We don't have a choice.
撤掉防护盾  马上光波传输
Be ready to drop the shields.As soon as they're down,
-把他们两个弄上来  -是  长官
-beam them directly to the infirmary.-Yes, sir.
萨曼  你们也一起上来吧
Sam, you should bring your Jumpers onboard at the same time.
明白  准备就位
Understood, we're in position.
好的
All right.
开始
Do it.
好了  飞船也上来了
We got 'em.Jumpers are in the bay.
展开防御
Shields up!
敌舰再次展开防护盾
Enemy vessel's raised shields again.
-攻击几乎无效  -继续开炮
-We scored several direct hits.-Keep firing.
现在形势怎样
How are we doing?
不太好  失去了亚光速
Not so good. Lost sublight,
超光速系统和武器都受损了
hyperdrive, and Asgard weapons.
动力源减少了55%
Life support's down at 55%.
防护盾呢
What about the shields?
还能挺一下  不过快不行了
They're holding for now but we're basically dead in the water.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
差点就失去你了
Thought we'd lost you there.
是啊  当时我也这么觉得
Yeah, well, for a second,I thought we lost me.
一切都会好起来的  对吧
It's gonna be okay though, right?
是的
Yeah.
不过还需要好好治疗
You need some serious work but you should...
现在可不能上战场了
you know, live to fight another day and all that.
现在情况怎样
what's going on? I guess
迈克尔比代达罗斯号早了一步吧
Michael showed up before the Daedalus.
是啊  我们迅速收起防护盾才能把
Yeah, we had to lower the shields
你们成功传送上来的
to beam you up here.
不好意思了
Sorry about that.
相信麦凯和卡特上校会摆平一切
I'm sure McKay and Colonel Carter will be able to fix it.
麦凯还活着吗
McKay is alive?
是啊
Yeah.
他和罗恩是从废墟中挖出来的
Yeah, he and Lorne were the only two to make it out of the rumble.
-我要回到前线  -不  听着
-I need to get back out there.  -No, no, look,
你会好起来的
you will be fine,
但可不是现在
but you're far from it now.
你失血很严重  需要手术
You've lost a lot of blood.You need surgery
要输血  这不能等
and a transfusion.I mean, this can't wait.
听着  医生  迈克尔来了
Look, Doc, Michael's here.
这意味着泰勒可能也在那
That means Teyla's probably on the ship.
这么近的距离我怎么可能坐得住
I'm too close to sit here and do nothing.
你还有事要做  那就是等着做手术
You're not gonna be doing nothing,you're gonna be laying here in surgery.
那必须...先随便包扎一下好了
That's gotta be like...It's gotta be a quick fix, just...
-不行  -只要几小时就行
-No.  -I need a few hours.
对不起  我不能那样做
I'm sorry, I can't.
我本来是有机会能
I have had the chance
救身边队友的
to rescue a teammate before.
只要伸一下手
And it slipped through my hands.
我不能再让这种事发生
I am not letting that happen again.
-干得好  -那当然
-Nice one.  -Of course.
虽然动力源还没回到最佳状态
Life support's still not working at full power but
但已经可以正常运转了
at least we won't freeze to death.
亚光速系统基本回到正轨
I've almost got sublight back online,
不过那些家伙正在猛攻防护盾
but the way these guys are taxing our shields,
剩余能源已不多
we won't have any power to spare anyway.
我们得逼出他们的主要武器
We need to take out the cruiser's main weapons.
想怎么用
Yeah, with what?
发动2至3次进攻
We can launch a 3 or 2 attack.
我也这么想
That's what I was thinking.
上校  凯勒医生说你还不能接任务
Colonel. Dr. Keller said you were out of commission.
她刚刚修正了诊断结果
She revised her diagnosis.
听着  我们有个想法
Look, we may have an idea.
或许能把泰勒救出来
Maybe a way to get Teyla back.
我们要逼出巡洋舰的主武器
We need to take out the cruiser's main weapons.
最简单的方法就是302s展开攻击
The easiest way to do that right now is to launch an attack with 302s.
我不觉得这是好方法
Well, I wouldn't exactly call that easy.
他们肯定会派出幽灵战机拦截
They'll send Darts to intercept them.
这正是我们计划的一部分
That's what we're counting on.
这轮攻击会让他们打开战艇的舱门
To launch them, they'll open the bay.
到时我们坐着隐形飞船
If we have a cloaked Jumper in place,
偷偷潜行进去就不会被发现
a team should be able to sneak onto the cruiser undetected.
救回泰勒  然后一路打回来
Find Teyla, bust her out and blast our way home.
总的来说  好像这次营救计划
As a rule, I like to keep daring
要一天才能完成啊
rescues down to one a day.
防护盾已剩下20%
Look, shields are already down to 20%,
被击破只是时间问题
it's just a matter of time before they fail completely.
她就靠我们了  史蒂文
She's over there, Steven,counting on us.
我可接受不了"不行"这个答复
I won't take "no" for an answer.
好吧  带上隐形飞船
All right, take a cloaked Jumper.
就位后马上出发
Radio us when you're in position.
-在医务室里到底发生了什么  -没什么
-What really happened in the infirmary?  -Nothing.
是不是打算告诉我  如果我去问珍妮弗
You're telling me, if I go down there and talk to Jennifer,
她会说你太适合做任务了
she'll tell me that you're fit for duty.
-我只想做好工作  -我也一样
-I'm just trying to do a job.  -So am I.
我工作的一部分就是
And part of my job is determining whether or not
看你适不适合工作
you're gonna be a liability on this mission.
所有指挥官里我最敬佩你
I have more respect for you than any commanding officer I've ever had but,
但我还是要回到飞船上  结束这一切
I'm getting on that Jumper,end of story.
最后我会去军事法庭认错的
I'll surrender for court martial when I'm done.
若楠和我两个人就能处理好这事
You know, Ronon and I could probably handle this.
或许你该留在飞船上
Maybe you should stay with the Jumper.
当然一起也可以
Or not.
-代达罗斯号  我们已就位  -收到
-Daedalus, we're in position.  -Confirmed.
发射302s
Launch 302s.
302s正在靠近
302s are approaching.
幽灵战斗机  来吧
Give me the Darts.
-它要关闭了  -我看到了
-It's closing.  -I see that.
-马上要关了  -知道了
-It's closing quickly.  -I got it.
代达罗斯号  我们已进入
Daedalus, we're in.
成功了  他们刚刚失去了主要武器
It worked.Cruiser just lost main weapons.
希望谢帕德一样好运吧
Let's hope that Sheppard has the same luck.
好了  只需要几秒钟
All right, this won't take more than a couple of seconds.
有麻烦了
That's troubling.
怎么了
What?
迈克尔居然对它作了远程修复
Michael's a lot further ahead with the repairs than I would have thought.
超光速系统还能用  要快点了
Hyperdrive's almost back online.We got to make this quick.
-具体要多快  -15分钟  没时间了
-What do you mean quick?  -15 minutes. It's not a lot of time.
现在可没那么多时间啊
No, it's not a lot of time. So...
不如直接告诉我们泰勒在哪好了
why don't you tell us where Teyla is, already?
好吧  好吧  好吧
All right, all right, all right.
行了
Got it! Okay.
跟我来
Follow me.
还是  你先吧
Or... you...
-约翰  -我们要进去了
-John?  -We're going to get down here.
没时间了
Not a moment too soon.
我们得把你弄回飞船上去
We got to get you back to the Jumper.
你还好吗
You okay?
-是肚子里的孩子  -哪里不舒服
- It's my baby.- What? Is something wrong?
不  我只是宫缩了快一个小时
No. I have been having contractions for over an hour now.
他们就要出来了
They're very close.
我快要生了
My baby's coming.
老天!
God!
不好意思
I'm sorry.
给我点时间
I just need a moment.
我可以抱她的  只是我现在也撑不住了
I'd carry her buddy but...I'm not really up to it.
-你准备好了吗  -没事  我能走
- Yeah. Okay, you're ready?- No. I can walk.
我需要点时间
I just need a moment.
伙计们  现在有点小问题
Say, friends,we have a small issue, here.
又怎么了
Oh, what now?
看样子迈克尔把推进器又开起来了
Looks like Michael got his hyperdrive back online.
正在消耗能量了
It's powering up
-能把它关掉么  -用这个可不行
- Can you shut it down?- Not from this little thing.
驾驶室在通道尽头
The drive room is down the corridor.
拿一个C-4炸药去肯定管用
You slap a C-4 charge on that thing,it should certainly shut it down.
-哪儿  -这  我有地图
- Where?- Here. I've a map.
好吧  若楠  你跟我来
All right. Ronon, you're with me.
我马上回来  没事的
I'll be right back.Everything is gonna be fine.
你照顾好她
You take care of her.
呃
So...
你怎么样了
how are you doing?
痛极了
The pain is very great.
哦  对的
Oh yeah.
我得过一次肾结石  真的是痛极了
Yeah I had a kidney stone once.Incredibly painful.
就和我的一样  所以我能了解
Same kind of thing from what I'm told.So I hear you.
实际上  我的猫也和我同时得的结石
Actually, my cat and I had oneat the same time.
我们在一起总没好事
We were not fun to be around,
它是因为总吃得太干  而我因为没喝水
He, 'cause he was eating the dry food,I wasn't drinking enough liquids.
所以你看我总喝水  因为我可不想再犯
That's why you always see me hydrating.I've no desire to experience that again.
-只是...  -很有意思  谢谢
- It's just...- Fascinating story.
好吧
Yes, no problem.
深呼吸  深呼吸
Okay just, just breathe?Breathe, okay?
-你在干吗  -给你助产  应该...
- What you doing?- It's Lamaze. It's supposed to...
我也不知道我在干吗  你需要我怎么做
I don't know what I'm doing.What do you need me to do?
在这儿  在这儿呢
Okay, there it is, there they are.
我要生了
The baby is coming!
坚持住  等回去了  凯勒会帮你接生
Hang on. We'll get back on the Deadelus,Keller can pull it out.
就要生了  现在！
The baby is coming now!
-快消耗光了  -给我C-4
- It's almost powered up.- Give me your C-4.
-把它给我  -我能行
- Give it to me.- I got it.
把它给我  不要什么都扛着
Give it to me.You don't have to do everything.
搞定了  准备好了吗
All right. You're ready?
走
Let's go.
好了  但愿我们离得够远
All right.Let's hope we're far enough away.
来  瞧瞧
Yeah, we'll see.
炸起来吧
Fire in the hole.
-怎么回事  -推进器爆炸了
- What happenend?- Hyperdrive just exploded.
不可能
No. That's impossible.
船体主能源供应不足
Main power is out across most of the ship.
-偶尔超负荷了?  -不太像
- An accidental overload?- Doesn't appear that way.
他们是怎么办到的
How did they do that?
我会查清楚的
I will look into it.
他们上来了
They're onboard.
他们是怎么上船的
How did they get onboard?
-就不能憋着不生?  -不可能  罗德尼
- Well, can't you just hold it in?- No, Rodney!
不会这么快的  不会这么快就生出来的
This doesn't happen this quick!No one has babies this quick!
我的羊水早就破了
My water broke quite a while ago.
我一直在试着...
I've been trying to...
噢  我看见脑袋了
Oh, I can see its head.
这是好事  这样才对  罗德尼
That's good.That's a good thing, Rodney.
我能碰么  我该做什么
Yeah but am I supposed to touch it?Am I allowed? I don't know what to do!
罗德尼
Rodney,
冷静  你得冷静点
calm down.I need you to be calm.
我不是医生  我从来就没当过医生
But I'm not an MD.I've never been an MD!
人类生小孩都生了几千年了
People have been having babies for thousands of years.
大多数时候都没有医生
Most without doctors.
没有医生死亡率就高
But before doctors the infantile mortality rate was very high.
差不多有三分之一了
Something like one in three.
相信我  医生真的很重要
No, a doctor is a very important part of this process, trust me.
现在没有医生了  得你来
There are no doctors around. You have to do this.
我们没的选了
We don't have a choice.
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
现在
Now,
你抓住他
you need to catch him.
－抓?  －是的  抓住他
- Catch him?- Yes. You need to catch him,
-我会用力推他出来  -天哪
- while I push him out.- Oh, God!
好吧 来
OK, well, just...
伸到下面  我打不好棒球的
Underhand him, all right.I've never been good at baseball.
罗德尼  拜托了
Rodney,Please.
我能行
Okay, I can do this!
虽然我还是有点怕  但是我们能行的
All right, I may have panicked a little back there but we're gonna do this!
我总是和小孩子处得好
I am great with kids.
小伙计  不顶嘴的小家伙
The little ones.The ones who don't talk back.
要出来了
Here he comes!
快了 快了
Okay. Almost there, almost there!
我抓到他了
I got him!
我接住了
是个男孩
It's a boy.
-小心他的脑袋  -对  对
- Watch his head.- Right, right. OK.
上帝啊
Oh, God!
该剪脐带了么  可以剪脐带了吧
Do I get to cut the cord?I can cut the cord now, right?
好了  来
OK, OK. Here you go.
就这样
Yeah. OK. So...
来  泰勒
Right, Teyla,
郑重介绍  这是你的儿子
I'd like to introduce you to your son.
我成功了  没有出什么差错
I got it! Didn't let it fall or anything.
你做得棒极了
You did a wonderful job.
真是太棒了
That's good, that's...
你很棒  罗德尼
You're good, Rodney.
我们会带你离开这里
We got to get you out of here.
若楠  帮我一把
Ronon, you may need to help me.
这样?
Ready?
-它为什么是隐形的  -你弄坏了?
- Why isn't it decloaking?- Let me see, did you break it?
不  不  飞船就是停在这儿的
No, no...We parked the Jumper right here.
-是的  -一点不差
- Yes.- One hundred percent.
飞船被人偷走了
Someone stole the Jumper.
大事不好
This is not good.
我就说了  你该留在这儿
I told you you should have stayed here.
这下子我们该怎么离开这里
How the hell are we supposed to get off this ship, now?
我刚接生了  今天的任务就差不多了吧
I just delivered a baby.That's not enough for today?
他们就没有什么逃生舱之类的东西么
Don't they have escape pods or things like that on the cruiser?
没有...
No, they...
等等
Wait...
我有法子了
I know...
我们去找一个终端机
We need to get back to a terminal.
它们多数能量都比较低
A lot of their internal power is down.
我可以使干扰台短路
Maybe I can short out the jamming code
这样代达罗斯号就可以把我们传送回去
we can get the Daedalus to beam us out.
很好  带路吧
Great. Lead the way.
别开枪  放我下来
Don't shoot! Put me down.
没关系的  约翰
It's all right, John.
这是迦楠
This is Kanaan.
他是孩子的父亲
He is the father.
这是我们的机会
This is our chance.
这些是我告诉过你的朋友
These are the friends I told you of.
他们会帮助你  帮你变回原来的自己
They can help you.Get back to your old self.
但是你得先帮我们
But first you have to help us.
我们得离开这条船
We must get off this ship.
你有法子么
Do you know a way?
是的
Yes.
-跟我来  -不是想冒犯你  泰勒
- Follow me.- No offence, Teyla.
我不相信这家伙
I don't trust this guy.
他之前就试过救我
He has tried to save me before.
所以我相信他
I trust him.
把武器给我
Give me your weapon.
说说你的计划
What's your plan?
长官  有艘幽灵战斗机向我们发出呼叫
Sir?We've got a Dart trying to hail us.
什么
What?
我来听下
Let me hear it.
约翰·谢帕德上校呼叫  验证码
This is Colonel John Sheppard.Authentication code:
喝彩  三角形  查理  阿尔法  万能词
bravo, delta, charlie, alpha, niner.
代达罗斯号请回话
Daedalus, please come in.
验证通过  谢帕德上校  你的船怎么了
Authenticated, Colonel Sheppard.What the hell happened to your Jumper?
我的都送回库了  情况紧急就先借用这个
I got all turned around in the garage.I was in a rush, I borrowed this Dart.
我的小组都被传送进了一个存储装置
I've got the team beamed into the storage device.
-你找到泰勒了?  -是的  还有孩子
- Do you have Teyla?- Yes, and the baby.
那孩子也被送进去了?
You beamed a baby into Wraith storage?
没有
No.
我现在正抱着呢
I got it right here.
那么
So...
那艘巡洋舰就随你处置
Feel free to do whatever you want to that cruiser.
收到
Copy that.
马克斯中校?
Major Marks?
击退那艘飞船
Please make that ship go away.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
上校  你可以回我们星球了
Colonel, head down to the planet
把你的组员传送回去  船也找个地降落
beam your crew out and land that Dart.
我想现在可以去星门拨号了
I'm sure you can dial up that Stargate now.
收到
Copy that.
-袋子里装啥呢  -那你的花呢
- What's with the bags?- What's with the flowers?
我准备去看泰勒
I'm going to see Teyla.
听说了吗  她的孩子是我接生的
You heard I delivered her baby?
听说了
I did.
而且听说她准备给宝宝起名罗德尼
And they tell me she's going to name him Rodney.
太棒了  真的吗
Yes! Really?
假的
No. Not really.
-真有意思  你去哪儿  -回地球一趟
- That's funny. Where are you going?- Back to Earth.
-为什么  -他们找到最后一个巴力克隆人
- What? Why?- They caught the last Ba'al clone.
Tok'ra要分离共生体  想让SG-1的人到场
The Tok'ra gonna extract the symbiote.They want SG-1 to put in an appearance.
再说了
Plus,
国际勘察顾问组织想要做个"详细的调查"
the IOA wants to do an exhaustive review
看看我接管的第一年做的怎样
of my first year in command, so...
-一定没什么好事  -你说笑吗
- That can't be good.- Are you crazy?
他们一定是想给你颁奖章了
They probably want to give you a medal.
这一年你做得很棒
You had a great year.
我知道我的意见不顶什么用
I know my opinion doesn't mean much to those folks, but...
不过我还是认为你做得很棒
I think you've done an excellent job.
我很庆幸是你接了这个工作
I'm glad you took the post.
罗德尼  谢谢  这些话对我很重要
Thanks Rodney, that means a lot.
告诉谢帕德军事法庭的事还会再缓缓
Tell Sheppard the court martial will have to wait.
好的 回头见
Sure. See you soon.
希望如此
I hope so.
手术要多长时间
How long will the surgery take?
医生说得几个小时
The Doc says a few hours.
或许一周都不能走路
I'll be off my feet for a week or so.
真难以置信你这样子还试图进行营救
I cannot believe you attempted to mount a rescue in your condition.
试图?
Attempt?
上一次我进攻时  我就成功了
The last time I checked, I succeeded.
孩子怎么样
How's the kid?
凯勒医生说他健康情况很好
Doctor Keller says he's perfectly healthy.
我想他一切都会很好的
I say he's perfectly everything.
那真是太棒了
It's great.
很棒
我要谢谢你
I want to thank you.
没这个必要
There's no need.
我一直都没有放弃  因为我知道
I never gave up hope, because I knew...
因为我知道你一定会来救我  约翰
I knew that you would come for me, John.
换成你  你也会这么做的
You would have done the same for me.
是的
Yes.
好啦
All right.
上校  你准备好了吗
You're ready, Colonel?
准备?
Ready?
在我看来  我好像没干什么
From my understanding,I'm... not doing anything.
那就可以了  你只需要安静地躺着
Yeah, that's right.You'll just have to lay still and...
让我来搞定你吧
let me play with your insides.
不好意思
Sorry.
我们走吧
Let's go.
你准备给孩子取什么名字
What are you going to name the kid?
如果你方便的话  我想叫他图门·约翰
Well, if it's all right with you,I was thinking of Tughan John.
用我父亲和你的名字命名
After my father and after you.
真的吗
Really?
这样啊
Well...
麦凯一定要不高兴了
McKay is gonna hate that.
我很荣幸
I will be very honoured.
那太好了
Very well.
图门
Tughan
约翰
John
艾玛根
Emmagan.
卡特上校
Colonel Carter.
伍尔希先生  你好吗
Mr Woolsey, how are you?
我很好  谢谢
Very well, thank you for asking.
这个评估要花很长时间吗
So, is this whole evaluation process gonna take very long?
亚特兰蒂斯还有很多事  我急着回去
There's a lot of work on Atlantis.And I'm kind of anxious to get back.
你一定是的
I'm sure you are.
可是
However,
组织认为找一个拥有不同技能的人
the IOA has decided that perhaps someone with a different skill set
或许能够更好的主持亚特兰蒂斯的事务
would be more suited to lead the Atlantis expedition now.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我来这儿是要通知你
I'm here to inform you that effective immediately,
你被免除指挥官一职  即刻起生效
you are being removed from command.
谁来代替我
Who's replacing me?
实际上
As a matter of fact,
是我
I am.